A Guide to the Letters of James Branch Cabell, 1922-1958
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters of James Branch Cabell, 1922-1958
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-l
This collection consists of 1 reel: positive; 35 mm.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1964 June 17.
Scope and Content Information
In this collection of letters, James Branch Cabell discusses his work, its publication and editions, especially The King Was in His Counting House; Hamlet Had an Uncle; and The First Gentlemen of America. Cabell also mentions Ellen Glasgow's literary interests and her health.
Recipients include Cabell's editors John Chipman Farrar, Stanley Rinehart, Adelaide Sherer, and Philip Wylie. Also included is a letter, ca. 1942, from Stephen Vincent Benét to Farrar complimenting and analysing Cabell's First Gentlemen of America.
These letters are on microfilm (M-1369), from originals in the Yale University Library. They are in the order in which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to ______ Parsons 1926 Feb 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1925 Jan 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Oct 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Sep 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Jul 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Jun 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Mar 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Feb 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1924 Feb 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Parsons 1923 Oct 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Henry Seidel] Canby 1935 Oct 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Canby 1935 Nov 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Canby 1932 May 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Canby 1923 Dec 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Dr._______ Millett 1937 Mar 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [William Lyon] Phelps 1933 Jul 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Miss McAfee 1922 Dec 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Wilbur Lucius] Cross 1921 Jan 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 Sep 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 May 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 May 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 May 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Cross 1920 Mar 16, TLS. [encl. clipping, re: Jurgen] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Swan 1946 May 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Stanley] Babb 1951 Mar 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Babb 1927 Apr 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Babb 1926 Oct 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to John [Farrar] 1958 Jan 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to John [Farrar] 1957 Apr 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [John] Farrar 1957 Jan 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [John] Farrar 1956 Dec 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Nov 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Oct 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Sep 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Jul 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Jun 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Jun 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Apr 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Mar 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Feb 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1956 Jan 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1955 Dec 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Oct 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Aug 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Aug 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Jul 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Jul 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1954 Jun 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 Dec 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Margaret Farrar 1953 Jul 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 May 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 May 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Margaret Cabell to Farrar 1953 May 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 May 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 Apr 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 Apr 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1953 Feb 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Nov 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Oct 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Sep 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Feb 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Feb 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1952 Jan 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Nov 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Sep 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to _______ Kempner 1951 Sep 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Jul 31, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from, TLS.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Jun 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Jun 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 May 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 May 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Apr 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Apr 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Mar 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1951 Jan 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1950 Jun 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Nov 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Sep 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Sep 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Miss ________ Sheffield 1949 Aug 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Aug 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Jul 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Mar 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1949 Feb 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Mrs. ________ Sheffield 1949 Feb 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1948 Nov 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1948 Nov 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1948 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Mrs. _______ Sheffield 1948 Sep 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1948 Jul 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar, Straus, and Co. 1948 Feb 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to _______ Straus 1947 Oct 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1947 Oct 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar and Straus 1947 Oct 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1946 Oct 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Apr 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to ________ Kane 1922 Oct 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Henry Seidel] Canby 1922 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to ________ Raney 1949 Jun 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Adelaide A.] Sherer 1947 Sep 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Adelaide A.] Sherer 1947 Jul 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer n.d., TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart and Co. 1947 May 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Miss Reese 1947 Feb 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Stanley M.] Rinehart 1947 Feb 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Nov 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Priscilla Cabell to Sherer 1946 Oct 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Sep 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Jun 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Apr 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Apr 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Mar 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Feb 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1946 Jan 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer n.d., TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Oct 27, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Oct 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Sep 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Aug 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Aug 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Jun 16, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 May 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Mar 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Jan 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1945 Jan 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip Wylie 1944 Nov 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1944 Nov 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar and Rinehart 1944 Oct 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip Wylie 1944 Oct 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1944 Oct 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 Sep 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip Wylie n.d., TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip Wylie 1944 Jul 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip Wylie 1944 Jun 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 Jun 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 May 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1944 May 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1944 May 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 Apr 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 Mar 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1944 Jan 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1943 Dec 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1943 Nov 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1943 Oct 5, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1943 Sep 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Oct 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Oct 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Sep 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Aug 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Jun 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Jun 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Apr 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Apr 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Apr 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Mar 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Mar 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1942 Mar 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1942 Feb 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1942 Feb 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1942 Jan 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1942 Jan 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Miss ______ Overton 1941 Dec 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1941 Oct 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1941 Oct 4, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from S[tephen]; V[incent]; B[enét] to Farrar [1941], TL. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Sep 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Aug 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Aug 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Aug 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Aug 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Jul 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Jun 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Jun 15, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1941 Jun 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1941 Jan 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1941 Jan 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1940 Nov 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1940 May 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1940 Feb 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1940 Jan 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1940 Jan 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1940 Jan 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Dec 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Nov 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Oct 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1939 Oct 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Oct 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Oct 5, Telegram
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Sep 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Sep 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1939 Jul 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1939 Jun 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1939 Jun 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 May 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1939 Feb 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Feb 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1939 Jan 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Nov 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Nov 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1938 Oct 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Oct 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Oct 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Oct 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Sep 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Miss _______ Anderson 1938 Sep 2, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Jul 31, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Sherer 1938 Jul 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Jul 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Jun 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Jun 10, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Dec 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1938 Jun 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 Jun 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Farrar 1938 May 22, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rinehart 1938 May 22, TLS. 1 p.